目前代码库中缺少评估
The codebase is now missing tests
机器人 RAG 流水的测试。
for evaluating the RAG pipeline of the chatbot.
让我们实现这些测试，用它们来调试
Let's implement these tests and use them to debug an error
机器人处理查询时的错误，并最终重构
that the chatbot is having processing the queries, and finally, refactor
机器人处理工具调用的方式。让我们开始吧。
how the chatbot handles its tool use. Let's dive in.
到目前为止，我们已了解如何快速熟悉代码库
So far we've seen how to get up to speed with codebases
并实现功能以构建更强大的体验。
and implement features to build a slightly more powerful experience.
现在，假设距离我们上次
Now let's go ahead and imagine that it's
处理这个应用已经
been some time since we've worked on this
过去了一段时间。我们想重新开始使用它。
application. We're coming back and we want to start using it again.
让我们回到应用，
So let's hop back to our application
询问关于第五课内容的详细信息。
and ask for some details on what's covered in Lesson 5.
我们预想会得到
We might expect to see a response
信息反馈，但现在出问题了。
that gives us information, but right now, something's wrong.
你可能想直接
It might be tempting to just
复制这个错误扔给 Claude，
copy this error, put it into Claude,
或者截个图期望它能解决问题。
take a screenshot, hope it solves the problem.
但我们要采取一种略有不同的方法。
But we're going to do something a little bit different.
我们不会只是寻求答案
Instead of just getting the answer that we might want
或者让 Claude 盲目尝试。
or leading Claude on some wild goose chase.
我们要采取更系统的方法。
We're going to take a bit more of a methodical approach here.
我们知道应用出错了，
We know that things are wrong in our application,
但也知道目前没有足够的测试
but we also know that we don't have too many tests here
来程序化地验证这一点。
to programmatically verify that that's the case.
所以，我们将输入一段提示词，
So what we're going to do is put in a prompt
它不仅提到了错误是什么，
that not only mentions what the error is,
还指定需要编写测试的地方。
but also specifies where we need to write tests.
回到代码库，
If we go back to our code base,
这个错误可能
the error we're looking at could be
源于多个 Python 文件。
from a variety of different Python files.
在 AIGenerator 中，我们处理与 API 的交互。
In our AIGenerator, this is where we handle interactions with Anthropic's API.
Prompt 或是
And there could be problems in the prompt
逻辑中可能
or even some of the logic
存在问题。
we have for getting this part working.
在 rag_system.py 中，
In our rag_system.py,
它是 RAG 全流程的编排者。
this is the orchestrator for everything that's happening with Retrieval Augmented Generation.
在 search_tools 中，我们定义了底层的工具
And in our search_tools, here's where we define the underlying tool
定义，那里也可能存在问题。
definition where there could potentially be problems.
所以，我们首先要求 Claude
So what we're going to ask Claude to do
为这些特定文件编写测试。
is write tests for these specific files just to start.
然后让 Claude 运行这些测试，
We're then going to ask Claude to run those tests
通过这种方式验证哪里坏了并
and through that, verify what is not working and make
进行修复。这种方法的强大之处在于：
the appropriate fix. What's so powerful about this approach
通过测试先行，我们
is by starting with our tests, we
可以建立稳固的基础，
can start to build a robust foundation
以便更好地开发代码库，
for building more off of the codebase
并准确理解为什么会失败。
and understanding when things go wrong, why they're failing.
打开 Claude 输入提示词。
So let's open up Claude and put in a prompt.
由于这个任务更有挑战性，
Since this is a little bit more challenging,
我们要开启 Claude 的扩展思维能力。
we're also going to ask Claude to think a lot.
这会分配更多
This is going to trigger Claude's ability
Token 用于
to enable extended thinking
思考过程。
and allocate a few more tokens
我们可以观察这个思考过程，
towards the thinking process. we're also going to see this process
如果发现方向不对，
and if something doesn't appear right, we
随时可以中断它。
can always stop Claude in its tracks.
我们会开启计划模式，
We'll go ahead and make sure the plan mode is on
因为我们希望在 Claude 开始写测试之前，
because first we want to make sure before Claude starts writing tests,
确保它理解了任务
it understands what it needs to
并获得我们的批准。
do and we can approve that process.
在读取必要文件时，
As we start to read the files necessary,
我们可以看到 Claude 的思考逻辑。
we're going to see Claude's thinking process.
不仅能看到它正在读取的文件，
We're not only going to see the files that we're reading,
还能看到它准备怎么做。
but also what it needs to examine and what it should do.
来看看 Claude 的计划。
So let's go see what Claude's plan has. It's
它似乎发现了一个配置问题，
It seems like there's some kind of configuration issue,
可能是复杂的工具调用失败点，
maybe some complex tool calling with failure points
或者是组件间的错误传播受限。
and some limited error propagation between components.
所以错误可能只是被某处截获了。
So it's possible that the error is just getting caught somewhere.
它随后建议基于这些文件
It's then going to propose a structure for tests
构建结构，这看起来不错。
based on these files, which looks good to us.
使用 pytest 框架并模拟
use the pytest framework and mock whatever
ChromaDB 中我们需要的部分
it is in ChromaDB that we need
来启动单元测试和集成测试。
to get some unit tests and integration tests up and running.
它开始创建
You can see right now it's starting to make
测试文件夹并编写测试。
a folder for my tests, where it'll be running.
这是一个好的开始。
writing these. It's a great start.
我们还要使用 UV 来安装
We'll go ahead and make sure we add
任何必要的依赖项。
any necessary dependencies here as well with UV.
安装依赖，
Let's go install our dependencies,
确保 pytest 运行正常。看起来不错。
make sure we have pytest working as expected, and that looks good.
这里也能看到思考过程，
We're also going to see the thinking part
确保结果符合预期。
here to make sure that we're doing what's expected.
在编写这些测试时，
As we start to write these particular tests,
我们可以浏览生成的代码。
we can start exploring the code that's been written for us.
这里有搜索工具的测试、
Here we can see tests for the course search tool,
Fixture 和 Mock。
fixtures and mocks that we need to make.
这是一个好的开始。
This looks like a good start. We'll
AI 生成器、RAG 系统
see the same thing for our AI generator.
和向量数据库也是如此。
and our RAG system and our vector store.
它似乎识别出了一个关键的
It seems like it's identified a critical
关键的配置问题，这可能解决了 Bug，
config issue which may solve the bug,
但写测试能给我们完整的保证：
but writing these tests is going to give us complete assurance
这就是问题所在，
that this is actually the problem
且修复是正确的。
and that this is the correct fix.
创建完测试后，使用 UV 运行它们。
Now that we've created these tests, let's run them using UV.
确保我们拥有正确的依赖项
Let's go make sure we have the correct dependencies
以按预期运行测试。
so that we can run those tests as expected.
根据它的发现，问题似乎出在
So from its finding, it's telling us that it's
max results 或是
seems like there's something wrong with these max results
我们向量搜索返回的
or the number of chunks that were
块数量上。来看看
returning when we perform our vector search. So let's see
查看 MAX_RESULTS 会得到什么。
what we're getting when we take a look at our MAX_RESULTS.
这确认了我们的问题。
And this confirms the issue that we have.
由于某种原因，它被设为了 0。
For some reason, this happens to be zero.
一旦我们修改这个值，不仅
Once we go ahead and change this, we should expect
测试会通过，
that not only our tests are working as expected,
我们也能得到完整的结果。
but that the results we get are complete.
我们可以通过查看确认
We can verify this by taking a look and
得到了预期的文件。
making sure we get the file that we expect.
Claude Code 正在收尾，
Now that Claude Code is wrapping up,
它提供了一份详尽的发现总结。
it can provide a comprehensive summary of its
我可以等待
findings, which I can wait to
或者如果我觉得没问题了，
see or if I feel good now,
可以中断它。
I can stop Claude in its tracks.
来看看它
But I'll take a look at what
给我的东西。它完成了调试。
it gives me. It's completed its debugging.
找到了关键问题，并创建了一些测试
It's found the critical issue, and it's created a few tests,
以及测试基础设施，
as well as some infrastructure to
以便后续继续运行。
keep running tests as we go forward.
去看看是否奏效。
Let's go see if this worked as expected.
回到浏览器开启新对话，
Back in the browser, I'll start a new conversation,
再次询问同样的问题，
and let's ask that same question again and
看是否得到预期结果。
see if we get the result as expected.
查询不再失败，而是返回了
Instead of the query failing, we should expect to see information
课程信息，这正是我们要的。
just about the lesson and that's exactly what we did.
我们不仅修复了
we have here. So not only have
Bug，还建立了强大的
we fixed the bug, we built for ourselves
基础设施来保障应用运行，
a powerful infrastructure to keep running the application off
确保后续新改动时，
of and make sure that as we make new changes,
不会在不知情的情况下破坏功能。
things are not breaking and we don't know why.
应用运行正常后，
Now that we got this application working,
聊聊代码库的
let's talk about a little bit of a refactor
一点重构。
that I'd like to make in the codebase.
清空并重新开始新功能。
Let's clear and start again with a new feature.
在 ai_generator.py 中，
So here in our ai_generator.py,
我们规定每次查询最多只能调用一次搜索。
we specify that we want one search per query maximum.
虽然这对于简单查询有效，
While this leads to the expected behavior for relatively simple
但当我们要进行更复杂的查询时，
when we want to start doing more complex queries,
对比不同课程的大纲，
comparing different courses, comparing their outlines,
我们需要不止一次工具调用。
we're going to need more than one tool call.
我们需要一个能迭代处理所有
So what we're going to need is some kind of environment
必要工具的环境，
where we can either iteratively go through all the tools necessary
或者递归解决问题。
or recursively solve that problem.
如果你熟悉这里的代码和生态，
If you're comfortable with this code and ecosystem,
看看我们这里的这个类，
you can take a look at the class that we have here,
它是一个直接与 Anthropic 模型
which is a relatively simple way
对话的简单方法，
to talk directly to Anthropic models
使用 SDK 设置参数并
using our SDK, set your base_params and
生成响应。但你可以看到，
generate a response. But you can see
在构建系统 Prompt 时，
here, as we build our system prompt,
在处理消息和工具时，
as we figure out the messages necessary and any tools,
没有迭代过程来累积
there's no iteration and back and forth to accumulate
必要的工具并进行
our tools necessary and have a
使用多个工具的多轮对话。
multi-turn conversation with multiple tools being used.
让我们重构它。我有一段很长的提示词，
So let's refactor that. I've got a pretty long prompt here,
我打算新建一个
so I'm going to go ahead and make
名为 backend-tool-refactor.md
a new markdown file and let's go call this
的 Markdown 文件。
backend-tool-refactor.md
在这个文件中，我想
In this file, I want to walk through the
展示我这段提示词，
prompt that I have where I'm
要求 Claude 重构
going to ask Ask Claude to refactor
后端 ai_generator.py
the backend ai_generator.py
以支持分轮次的多次调用。
to support two calls in separate rounds.
我描述了当前的
The current behavior is what I'm describing
以及期望的行为。
as well as the desired behavior.
虽然这不是必须的，
While this might not be required,
但给 Claude 尽可能多的信息
it's often helpful, as we've seen,
通常很有帮助，
to give Claude as much information as possible,
特别是当任务复杂时。
especially when the tasks are a little bit more complex.
我们还提供一个示例流程。
We're also going to give Claude an example flow.
比如搜索讨论相同主题的
Something like search for a course that
其他课程。
discusses the same topic as another course.
让 Claude 明白要做什么。
Just to give Claude a sense of what needs to be done.
注意，这里有几个不同的
Notice here, there are a couple of different
工具需要按预期使用。
tools that need to be used as expected.
给 Claude 一些要求，
We'll give Claude some requirements,
还有一些提示，
and then a couple of notes as well
确保我们在做正确的事。
to make sure we're doing the right thing.
我们要确保编写的是
We're going to make sure that
验证外部行为的测试，
we write tests that verify external behavior
而不是关注内部状态细节。
instead of worrying about internal state details.
我还要求 Claude
Or we're also going to ask Claude to
构思几种不同的方案。
do is figure out a couple different plans.
先不要写代码，
Don't implement any code,
而是派两个子代理来头脑风暴方案。
but dispatch two subagents to brainstorm potential options.
我不确定最优的重构方案是什么。
In this situation, I'm not exactly sure what the optimal refactoring is.
所以我给 Claude 机会让它
So instead of letting Claude Code decide just one
并行思考
option, I'm actually going to give it the opportunity
多个选项。
to figure out multiple options in parallel.
使用这段特定的提示词，
So let's use that particular prompt
我会关闭自动接受编辑，
and I'll turn off auto accept to make sure
以便我在过程中
that as I'm going through, I can
确认每一个
confirm each of the changes that
改动。运行提示词。
I want. So let's run that prompt.
应该能看到两个并行的子代理
We should expect to see the two parallel subagents
通过 task 工具被派发出去。
being dispatched using a tool called task.
随着这些代理的派发，
And as we see those agents dispatched,
会看到两个
we'll start to see two plans
解决问题的方案。
for how we can solve this problem.
然后由我们决定实现哪一个。
It's then up to us to decide which one to implement.
可以看到它们在并行操作，
We can see that both of these are operating in parallel,
读取文件并想出两种不同的途径。
reading across files and figuring out two different approaches for this refactor.
看来它已经给出了
So it looks like it's come back with
处理此问题的建议。
some recommendations for how best to tackle this.
一个是迭代式的，另一个更全面。
One approach is iterative, another more comprehensive.
可以看到 Claude 实际上
We can see here that Claude is actually going
给了我们选择权：是选更具长期维护性的 B，
to give us an option to choose either option B
还是选更稳妥实现的 A。
for better long-term maintainability or option A for a safer implementation.
再向上滚动一点，
scroll up more. If I scroll up more, I
我能看到它想做什么的细节。
can get some details into what it's trying to do.
一个支持工具处理的迭代，
One option supporting some iteration for handling tools,
另一个是稍微复杂的
the other for a slightly more complicated implementation
多轮逻辑和辅助方法实现。
for multi-round logic with different helper methods for that process.
第一眼看，方案 A 更简单。
From first glance, it seems like approach A is a bit simpler.
那我们就从方案 A
So why don't we start with
开始吧。我选择方案 A，
that? I'm going to select approach A,
但我也要开启计划模式，
but I'm also now going to enable plan mode
确保有一个全面的计划
to make sure I have a comprehensive plan and
并在正式修改前批准它。
can accept before making the changes that I want.
实现方案 A。
Let's implement approach A.
获取详细计划来验证
and get a more detailed plan to verify
这正是我们想要的。
that this is exactly what we want to do.
我们知道需要修改
We know that there needs to be some modification
调用工具的方式，
in the way that which we call these tools,
但在让 Claude Code 编写代码前，
but let's make sure this is all being
确保一切都在正确的地方
done in the right place before we go ahead
进行。
and have Claude Code write the solution for us.
来看看这里要做什么。
Now let's take a look at what's being done here.
更新方法签名以支持最大轮数，
We'll update our method signature for a maximum number of rounds,
更新系统 Prompt，最核心的重构
update our system prompt, and here where the
在于 handle tool execution。
core refactoring is done in our handle tool execution.
如果符合预期，
If this is done as expected, we
应该能看到用户查询、
should see the user query, we should see
多次工具调用以及最终响应。
multiple tools being called and then a final response.
这不应影响其他部分，并能解决问题。
This shouldn't modify anything else and should solve the problem for us.
可以看到这是向后兼容的，
We can see here that this is backwards compatible,
且不涉及内部 RAG 或 API 端点的修改。
and we're not changing the internal RAG system or any API endpoints.
让我们继续，看它是否
So let's proceed and see if
能解决我们的问题。
this can solve our problem for us.
看它的实现过程：
As we see what's being implemented,
修改现有方法，
we can see changes to existing methods,
最重要的是，我们可以在这里看到
and most importantly, we can see here that
更新并运行测试
we're updating the tests and running the tests
以验证实现是否正确。
to verify that the implementation works correctly.
不需要切换到浏览器
Instead of context switching to the browser
或找别人测试，
or asking other people to test,
在 Claude Code 终端里
I can do this all from inside the terminal
就能搞定。
in Claude Code.
更新系统 Prompt，
So we'll see here, we're going to update our system prompt,
确保测试符合预期。
make sure that our tests are as expected.
添加一个测试确保
And then we'll add a test to make
顺序工具调用正常。
sure the sequential tool calling works as expected.
运行测试，确保通过。很好。
Let's run our tests, make sure they're passing as expected.
回浏览器验证一下。
Let's verify in the browser, this is doing what
首先询问
if you want. Let's try asking first
某一节课的细节。
for a details of a course's lesson.
瞧，
So here we can see
我们不仅得到了信息，
that not only are we getting this information,
还得到了预期的标题。
but also the title here as well, as expected.
我们得到了关于这节课的信息、
We're getting information about this lesson,
章节以及讨论的话题。
as well as some of the sections and topics discussed.
现在做点更复杂的。
Now let's do something a little more complex.
这里能看到标题的特别之处在于：
What's so special about seeing the title here is
只靠一次工具调用是得不到它的。
that we don't get that with just one tool call.
第一次工具调用只给出大纲。
The first tool call just gives us an outline of the course.
第二次才给出细节
The second tool call gives us that detail
和标题。
of the particular lesson and in our case the title.
现在问：还有其他课程涵盖了
Now let's ask, Are there any other courses that cover
MCP 课程第五课相同的主题吗？
the same topic as Lesson 5 of the MCP course?
为了回答这个问题，我们需要
In order to do this, we're going
需要进行多次工具调用
to need to make multiple tool calls
获取特定 MCP 课程信息
to get information about this particular MCP course
和大纲，再获取其他课程的信息进行
and outline and then information about other courses and their outlines
对比看是否有重合。
to see if there's any overlap.
遗憾的是，看来确实没有
Unfortunately, it looks like there are no other courses
其他课程涵盖构建 MCP 客户端的内容。
that cover building an MCP client, which does seem accurate.
在本课中，我们学习了如何使用 Claude Code
In this lesson, we've seen how to use Claude Code to
修复 Bug 并编写全流程测试。
not only fix bugs, but write tests throughout the entire process.
我们建立了稳固的基础，
We built for ourselves a solid foundation to keep coding on
进行了重构以处理更复杂的查询。很好。
and made a nice refactor to get more complicated query answers appropriately.
下一课中，我们将通过运行多个
In the next lesson, we'll improve our
会话并使用 Git worktrees
productivity by running multiple sessions of Claude Code
来提升效率，确保不会
and making sure we don't have overlaps or
发生重叠或覆盖。回头见。
overwrites using Git worktrees. I'll see you there.